# **Anders Brujordet**

# Lead Platform Engineer

I started out as a Java consultant focusing on Clean Code and agile methodologies, but I quickly got fascinated by the power and e Scala. This lead me to Finn no where I got to learn from great developers. At Finn I also tried to improve the CI/CI platform and in do parent company. I was hired to be part of the Delivery team in Schibsted to provide a delivery Platform for 1500 developers. When the many of the areas caught my interest, and I later joined VPS to help them create a Delivery Platform from scratch while also focusing

At home I'm a dad, power lifter, guitarist and hobby tinkerer. This might by why DevOps and security resonate so well with me. I've among other things the next train to leave from my local station. I've build, soldered and programmed my own silenced mechanical home and at work. When kubernetes was made available I was quick to create my own cluster at home using <u>Raspberry pis and Le</u> utilities report metrics and logs using Prometheus, Grafana and Graylog.

#### Experience

#### 2019 - present

#### CI/CD Platform Lead - Verdipapirsentralen

At VPS I've been able to single handedly try to implement a full Delivery Platform for one of Norway's most critical financial institution build, code analysis, deployments and engineering productivity, but also contribute in other teams and with security improvements. Key technologies: Jenkins, OpenShift, Ruby, JavaScript, Java

2016 - 2019

# Tech Lead & Senior Software Engineer at SPT in Schibsted Media Group - Schibsted

I was brought into Schibsted to help create their global Delivery Platform for 1500 developers. My roles included Developing and ru deployment pipelines. The responsibility of the team was to enable Schibsted's developers to quickly build, test, deploy and manageravis Enterprise. I also held the role as Tech lead and Technical product owner for CI.

Key technologies: Spinnaker, Travis, Java, Groovy, Python, JavaScript, AWS, Google Cloud and Kubernetes.

2014 - 2016

#### Senior Developer at Finn.no

I joined Finn to be part of their renowned API team which are know to be excellent Scala developers. I learned a lot from them while internal and public API. After a while I started investing more time in their Delivery Platform and especially focusing on the CI/CD pa Key technologies: Scala, SBT, python, varnish

2011 - 2014

#### Java Consultant at Knowit

As a consultant at Knowit it got to work on one of Norway's earliest DevOps driven projects with the Oslo municipality. I also got a tworking for Kommuneforlaget, where we created a data warehouse from scratch.

Key technologies: Java, Scala, maven, ruby, Spring, git

2010 - 2011

# Developer at SiriusIT

As a engineer in "NAV - Pensjonpgrammet" I took part in development and testing of the governmental letter templating system wh project to date.

Key technologies: Java, Scrum, Python

#### Training

# 2013

#### Functional Programming Principles in Scala - Coursera

The class gives an introduction into functional programming in Scala. The class is taught by Martin Odersky, the creator of Scala, as with a score of "89.6% with distinction".

#### 2010

# Oracle Certified Java Programmer 6 - Oracle

The class gives an introduction into functional programming in Scala. The class is taught by Martin Odersky, the creator of Scala, as with a score of "89.6% with distinction". The official Java Certification was completed with a pass.

#### Education

### 2008 - 2010

# Master of Computer Science at NTNU

The degree focused on all aspects of data retrieval and storage, resulting in a master thesis on Finding an Optimal Approach for Ind

#### 2005 - 2008

# Bachelor of Computer Science at NTNU

A broad focus on all aspects of computer science included programming, databases, operating systems, networking data structure

#### Personal Info





Address

Vestbybakken 5, 1900 Fetsund, Norway

E-mail

anders@brujordet.no

Blog

blog.brujordet.no

#### Skills

Backend



Frontend



DevOps



Cloud



Network



Security



Design

